[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien tasa automation
tutorial as you all know I already
published 41 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts and I already published
around 26 YouTube videos covering
advanced level
Concepts so from past two YouTube videos
we started working on multi-user
workspaces in trient Tasco so now let us
understand how can you create and manage
the branches in multi-user
workspace this is our lesson 42 in terms
of overall tasa automation Concepts and
this is our lesson 27 in terms of
advanced level
Concepts in this
lesson we are going to explore some more
features of multi-user
workspace I'm going to teach you how can
we create the branches and then how can
we manage the branches and how can we
delete the branches within trient TSA
when you are using multi-user
workspace please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
publish more videos thank
you okay so let us first understand what
do you mean by create and manage
branches so if you are familiar with
GitHub or git
reposit everyone knows that in an
organization whenever you maintain the
code
Base by automation team or by Developers
you need to have a common
repository to check in and check out
your code Base by multiple team members
so that is where this multi-user
workspace came into picture right so we
created multi-user workspace and we
created a repository for multi user
workspace in our previous two video
sessions but now apart from create
a multi-user
repository you need to maintain the
branches so basically you need to have a
one master branch and then you need to
have a separate
branches for either different
applications or different modules or for
different teams let's assume you are
maintaining a very big project
and there are multiple teams working on
this particular big project and there
might be chances of having multiple
applications and each application might
have multiple team members or multiple
teams so in that
case you should have a master
Branch where the entire automation code
once it is reviewed exec Ed successfully
right so then you need to move this
working
quality code base are the tasar scripts
to The Master
Branch however multiple team members
might work on multiple applications or
they might work on different
modules
and we can create Branch for each team
so that they can work on their own
applications and branches within their
Branch let's assume you have three team
members
teams so you can create three different
branches so that each team can work on
their own Branch so once they complete
working on their own
branches the lead will be reviewing
their branch code right they are going
to review all their test cases they're
going to execute the test cases to make
sure that whatever the automated test
cases that are working as expected and
then admin user will come into picture
and then he is going to
merge this Branch level code base to the
master
Branch right so that's why we need to
maintain a separate Master Branch but we
need to maintain separate branches at
application Level or at teams
level see the diagram this is your
master Branch presenting in blue color
and these are your branches from the
team
members so let's say this is team a team
B Team C right team a will be working on
their own changes and they'll be
automating and they will be executing
the test cases and make sure everything
working fine team be working on their
own modules and they'll be creating
their own test cases they will execute
and they'll make sure everything working
fine
once everything is pushed into their own
branches now the code base has to merge
into a master Branch so that it will
have latest and greatest workable test
case automation
suite and this we will be using for the
release
execution okay so that is what I'm going
to explain in this session how can we
create master branch in tric tasa how
can you create branches at Team level in
trient tasa and then how can you merge
all the changes done in their individual
branches to the master Branch right all
this I'm going to explain so let us see
what is our first agend item first we
are going to create a Master branch and
log into the master Branch let us go to
our trient tasa so this is my tric tasa
so let me create a master Branch first
for that you need to create a workspace
I'm going to click on create new I'm
going to explain end to endend process
okay how in real time projects how does
it works okay so here I already
explained you we need to select SQ light
for multi-user workspaces right and I
don't want to use any existing
repository because I'm creating a new
reposit I'm going to name this new
repository as
multi
user Master because I'm creating master
so because I'm creating master I'm going
to create admin user as well I'm just
providing username and
and
password because I'm creating the master
Branch so that I can access this master
Branch by using admin user okay I
created admin user as well okay for this
master branch called multi-user Master
Okay and then immediately click on okay
so now you'll be asking to enter your
admin credential whatever just now we
created so now creation of new workspace
is
successful now it will ask you to
provide your username and password for
admin okay I'm logging as an admin user
so once you log in let's open our
project now okay so this is our project
and we named the project as
multi-user Master right that's what I'm
going
to see here and if you see all your
objects got checked out so let me create
one quick uh test case in test case
section I'm going to right click on this
test case folder then create a new test
case I'm going to name this as
tc01 okay and then I'm going to create
another test case is
tc02 let's assume okay now
this is the master Branch I'm going to
check in all the changes now you need to
check in the changes once you log in
let's go back to our
presentation then what you need to do
create a branch for master Branch okay
so let's first complete creation of
Master Branch so we completed creation
of Master Branch now and then we checked
all our changes in the master Branch
generally we never work directly on the
master Branch but I'm just making sure
that some data exist in our Master
Branch already okay now what I'm going
to do we need to create a branch for
master branch of multi-user workspace
this is your master Branch now let's
assume I have a two different teams
working on two different modules so I
need to
create two branches for two different
teams so as an admin User it's my
responsibility to create branch
right two branches how can we create
branches you simply right click on
project so let me just check out this
project first of all okay so you need
not to check out the project but better
we check out the project okay right
click and then click on create Branch
okay you'll be clicking on create Branch
as soon as you click on create Branch
it's going to ask you to name the branch
what I'm going to do I'm going to name
this Branch as
team
a branch team a branch okay I named this
now if you read the message it says
Branch team a branch was created
successfully in order to work with the
new Branch save all the changes to
current workspace close the current
workspace and create a new workspace
with newly created Branch remember this
correctly okay so now let's click on
okay now I want to create another Branch
again go to Project root
folder click on create Branch here I'm
going to say Team
B Team B
Branch click
on okay again your team be Branch was
created successfully save all the
changes in the current workspace close
the workspace create a new workspace and
select Branch Team B Branch Okay click
on okay now we need to check in all
these changes I checked in all the
changes where I created two different
branches for two different team
members done now let's go back here we
created a branch Now log into newly
created Branch by creating a new
workspace so to log into New Branch you
need to close this particular workspace
I'm going to close the
workspace and you need to create new
workspace need to create new workspace
now let us create new workspace click on
create
new for creating new workspace we are
creating workspace for the branch let's
say I'm team a member in real time not
the same person is going to log into the
branch
so a team member from Team a will be
logging in so now let's assume I'm
playing the role of team member who is
part of Team a so that means I need to
create a workspace go
here select SQL light and here you need
to select use existing
repository and here what is our existing
repository our existing repository we
just created just now right
our existing
repositories let me expand this this one
multi-user master this is my existing
repository multi-user Master under
multiuser master common
repository select this this is my
existing repository you need to select
that that's why I checked use existing
repository because I already created an
existing repository for my Master
multi-user workspace I selected that now
because I'm a team member from Team a I
need to select a branch team a
branch select team a
branch then so till now what we did we
selected Master Branch when we create
the new workspace workspace so we never
selected this Branch At All by default
Master will be taken
so now this time I'm going to select
team a
branch and then I would like to name
this as team a
workspace team
a workspace I'll just say team a okay
this is my new workspace team a as my
new workspace and then click on
okay so now as soon as you click on okay
now he's creating a new workspace
with a team way team a
branch not master Branch so now again I
would like to log in as admin only
okay so generally whoever the user from
Team a he need to provide his own
credentials so if you see here let's go
to Project
now if you see the project name you are
seeing as multi-user Master even though
the project name is same don't get
confused if you see here on top right I
can see here my workspace is team a
workspace team a. twws that means I'm
accessing team a workspace and also if
you see here the branch it is not
showing me as Master Branch instead it
is showing me as Branch team a branch
that means I'm accessing my
Branch related to team a I'm not
accessing Master Branch now as a team
member I can do a number of changes in
this Branch because I'm not going to
disturb the master branch that I created
earlier now let's assume as a team a
member I would like to create some more
test cases just check out this SK
section and I would like to create uh
let's say I I want to auto at a module a
test case and then I also want to
automate
module P related test case let's assume
I automated all these two test cases and
I'm going to check in all my
changes okay so let's go back to our PBT
now we created a new branch and then
check out the test case folder and
create new test cases and check in your
changes so now I created a new test
cases in team a branch and I checked in
all my changes right and then let's go
back here now close the branch and open
open Master Branch so what I'm going to
do instead of opening the master Branch
now I'm going to close this team a
branch because let's assume all team a
related work is done we say we I mean
your team lead has reviewed it
everything working fine you make sure uh
test
execution uh you created the execution
list and you executed your test cases
and everything you signed off on Branch
team a branch you provided sign off on
team a branch but you cannot use this
code base as is because you have a
master Branch you need to merge all
these changes to your master
Branch right so before that let's close
this workspace and I want to do some
changes in Team B Branch as well so for
that I want to create a new workpace now
let's say I am a user of Team
B okay let's select SQL light as a team
B user I will be selecting the branch
Team B this time and I'm going to name
this as Team B right I'm using existing
repository this is my existing reposit
itory which I created for my master
Branch okay remember that your existing
repository is related to master branch
and under that you already created Team
B Branch I selected Team B Branch I
named workspace as Team B click on
okay so your workspace per team be is
created
successfully for the user related to
team now you user related to Team B will
be providing his own
credentials okay and click on
okay now PB is going to work on their
own modules let's assume I want to work
on because see he here he can see only
again Master Branch Only If You observe
closely here let's go to your project
Explorer you will have a project name as
same as your master Branch but here if
you see now you can see team. twws that
means it's tmb related workspace and you
can see the branch as Team B branch that
means it is team be related branch and
if you see here I can see only two test
cases which we created in during
creation of Master Branch okay so Master
Branch data can be viewed by every team
member or in any branch okay now let me
create now this team B wants to work on
module C and D team a team team a worked
on module A and B now Team B they're
going to create test cases let's create
a test case called module
C and then again I want to automate
module
D okay and now you lead will make sure
that whatever the test cases you
automated it works fine you execute it
and everything you sign off right
everything seems to be good now Team B
will be checking their changes from Team
B
Branch done
now team a team B they did their own
changes and checked in now you need to
merge these brand changes now see both
both the teams signed off everything
they said yes everything is working fine
now these team a and team be changes
needs to merg into the master Branch so
that that Master Branch can be
considered as a
final output of your Automation and
those test cases those test cases can be
run against your new
release right so let's for that let's
close close this team be
Branch now let us go back to
our Master Branch now let me access my
master BR as an admin user see we are
going to inform that corresponding teams
will inform okay we are done with our
all changes and everything is working
fine right now your administrator will
come
to this multi-user master Branch he's
going to open multi-user Master
branch and and admin user
will select provide his
credentials admin user provides his
credentials then we'll be logging in so
now now this admin user if you see here
now you can see only two stest Cas now
what I'm going to do I'm going to merge
the changes done by team A by using team
a branch okay for that I'm what I'm
going to do right click on this and
click on merge so before that let me
just check out this okay I'm going to
check out this and then right click on
this project folder and click on merge
Branch now here I would like to select I
want to merge the branch changes related
to team so you see clearly You observe
clearly we have only test two test cases
test case one and test case 2 okay now
as soon as I merge the branch team a it
going to say the branch will be
permanently deleted when you check in
the changed objects that means see once
I merge team a branch related changes to
master Branch your team a branch will be
deleted so make a note okay so now
because team a signed off saying that
everything is working fine so that's why
I can simply merge them click on okay
now you can see now okay you have now
module a module B if you remember
correctly team a worked on module a and
module B so that means all the changes
related to team a are now merged into
your master Branch now checking all
these
changes now in the same way I would like
to March the changes related to
Team B from Team B Branch okay for that
again right click and click on merge
Branch this time I have to select team B
Branch click on okay so again the branch
will be permanently deleted when you
check in the changed objects click on
okay you can see module C and module
D are came into Master Branch from your
team B Branch so and then you can simply
checking all the changes that means now
all the changes done by team A and Team
B are merged into your master
Branch so delete Branch how can you
delete the branch so we already deleted
some branches already right so simply
you right click on this project and
click on delete branch
so if you click on delete Branch now I
can see Team be Branch I created
recreated it and you can simply click on
okay so this will delete your team B
Branch okay Team B Branch deleted
successfully okay
so this is how you can
maintain Master branch and you can
manage branches at Team level or
application Level and then you can merge
merge all your branch changes to the
master branch and then you can delete
the branches so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries hope
you all understand the concepts of
creating and managing the branches as
part of this session you have learned
how can you create a master branch and
then how can you create an individual
branches for master branch of multi-user
workspace and how can you merge the
chain changes of each individual Branch
to the master Branch as an admin
user please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
[Music]
you